DEEPAK YADAV

Consultant at Sony (Al and Machine Learning)

portfolio

dky.united@gmail.com

+91-7376710930

c deepak7376

Bangalore, India

in dky7376

SUMMARY

Experienced AI and ML Consultant with over 5+ years of dynamic roles, including a significant tenure at Sony. Proven in edge AI, and model development. Expert in TensorFlow, and PyTorch. Bringing innovation and technical excellence to dynamic teams.

SKILLS -

Languages: Python, SQL, JavaScript, C++, C.

Technologies: AWS, Docker, Kubernetes, MLflow, Kube-

flow,Tensorflow, PyTorch, React.js, Django, Flask, Flutter, Hugging-face, Keras, NLTK

EXPERIENCE

Jun 2021 - Present Consultant

Sony, Bengaluru, Karnataka

- · Spearheading the Esensor project, leading edge AI implementation using Sony's IMX500 device.
- Steering the development and deployment of AI models for the SFAID project, showcasing automation in industrial packaging applications.
- Conducting comprehensive analysis to optimize model performance, ensuring streamlined inference processes.
- · Tools: Python, Computer Vision, TensorFlow, PyTorch, Streamlit, Django, React-js, SQLite

Dec 2019 - Apr 2021 Associate Data Scientist

Activa Inc., Hyderabad, Telangana

- Led the development of an innovative AutoML platform, automating the entire model selection and training process.
- Contributed significantly to the AutoML pipeline's design, particularly in hyperparameter selection using genetic algorithms.
- · Tools: TensorFlow, Scikit-learn, Python, Docker, Flask, AWS EC2, REST, CI/CD.

Aug 2019 - Dec 2019 Data Science Intern

Activa Inc., Hyderabad, Telangana

- Developed a computer vision model using Mask-RCNN for detecting internal cracks within aircraft engines.
- $\bullet \ \ \text{Leveraged deep learning techniques to create a highly accurate and efficient solution for crack detection.}$
- · Tools: Computer Vision, Object Detection, Mask-RCNN, Python, TensorFlow, OpenCV.

Jul 2018 - Jun 2019 Postgraduate Researcher

IIEST Shibpur, Howrah, WB

- Conducted in-depth studies on various fault-detecting methods in Wireless Sensor Networks (WSNs), including statistical-based and machine learning-based approaches.
- · Developed an innovative algorithm for detecting faulty nodes in Wireless Sensor Networks (WSNs).
- Tools: Statistics, Wireless Sensor Networks, Arduino, Wireless Networking, Python, Machine Learning.

OPEN SOURCE PROJECTS -

Generative AI **Text to Image Generation using Stable Diffusion**

link

High-performance image generation using Stable Diffusion in KerasCV.

LLM Based Custom Pdf Chatbot

link

Streamlit web application designed to facilitate interactive and context-aware conversations with users based on the content of PDF documents.

Wireless Network WSNFault

link

Statistical fault detection algorithm for Wireless Sensor Networks (WSNs).

EDUCATION -

Aug 2017 - Jun 2019 Indian Institute of Engineering Science And Technology, Howrah, WB

Master of Technology in IT

Relevant Coursework: Machine Learning, Algorithms, Information and Coding Theory, Advanced Database Management System.

GPA: 7.0/10.0

Aug 2010 - Jul 2014 United College of Engineering and Research, Allahabad, UP

Bachelor of Technology in ECE

Relevant Coursework: Signal and Systems, Microprocessors, VLSI Design and Embedded System. GPA: 6.8/10.0

LANGUAGES